Guide to the Stephen Harmon Photographs 1942, 1968-2017 PR 362
New-York Historical Society
- Series D.V. New York City "Street Show", 1995-2017; 11.2 Megabytes (18 digital images in JPG format)
  Somewhat similar in scope to the Street Portraits series, this series includes images that center on people and the street life of New York City, beginning in the 1990s and extending into the twenty-first century. Unlike the earlier series, though, which tended to focus more tightly on "portraits" of individuals or couples/small groups, the "street show" series, to use a term Harmon often used in categorizing some of these images, tend to capture individuals in the context of some activity. These range from the quotodian, such as people waiting at a bus stop or children eating pizza, to the slapstick, such as a person slipping on ice, to the desperate, such as panhandling. Also unlike the content of Street Portraits, which was defined entirely by the photographer, this series includes both those images referred to as part of New York's "street show" by Harmon and similar images identified by the processing archivist. The container list descriptions were typically composed by the processing archivist in order to convey the literal content of the image; Harmon's email, preserved with the image, often includes his humorous captioning, his particular points of emphasis in the image, or other commentary.
  The series is arranged in chronological order by the date of the photographs.
  - Busker with sign "Tell me off for $1.00" (1 photo + 1 email), undated (Digital folder 20170403, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Woman and child at apartment window in Chinatown (1 photo + 1 email), 1981 December (Digital folder 20171016, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Panhandlers at car windows (1 photo + 1 email), 1995 (Digital folder 20170616, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - Woman getting a shoe shine on the street (1 photo + 1 email), 1998 January (Digital folder 20171020, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - Hasidic Jews in Williamsburg (2 photos + 1 email), circa 2000 (Digital folder 20170814, Digital file 3_1-2, email)
  - Pedestrians in SoHo (1 photo + 1 email), 2004 September (Digital folder 20170202, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - Chess players, Washington Square Park (3 photos + 1 email), 2006 October (Digital folder 20170514, Digital file 4_1-3, email)
  - People waiting at bus stop. West 72nd Street (1 photo + 1 email), 2008 October (Digital folder 20170609, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - 9th Avenue construction crew (1 photo + 1 email), 2015 July (Digital folder 20150721, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Man upside down having slipped on the snowy sidewalk (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 March? (Digital folder 20170319, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Woman sitting at sculpture of sitting woman (1 photo +1 email), 2017 March? (Digital folder 20170327, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - Tattooed person (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 March? (Digital folder 20170329, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - Nude in window overlooking High Line (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 March (Digital folder 20170331, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Dog in shopping cart pushed by pedestrian on 5th Avenue (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 April? (Digital folder 20170419, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Couple embracing (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 June 4 (Digital folder 20170604, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Man smoking near medical care center (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 July 4 (Digital folder 20170705, Digital file 3_1, email)
  - Children and adults eating pizza, etc. on bench by a Starbucks (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 October 22 (Digital folder 20171023, Digital file 3_1, email)
- Series D.VI. Subway Life, 1980s-2017; 47.3 Megabytes (214 digital images in JPG format)
  The series includes photographs primarily of people as passengers in the context of the New York City train transit system, which includes both underground and elevated stations and tracks. These images include people within the train cars and on station platforms. There are also many photos not centered on people, including images of signage, turnstiles, train exteriors, ticket booths, and other infrastructure.
  Generally, the series holds images taken from within the transit system, not from outside it. Accordingly, most of the images are interior views, with few street level views. Street level views of stations and the like can more commonly be found in Series D.II and D.III (Buildings, Parks, Cityscapes). In the container list below, "interior" refers to images taken inside of train coaches; "station" refers to both platforms and to areas of the station and network of connecting tunnels leading to the platforms; and "passengers" refers to people anywhere in the system.
  The general concept of the series was defined by Steve Harmon and he often, but not always, identified photographs that he considered part of it. Photographs not so identified by Harmon but clearly consistent with the theme were included by the processing archivist.
  The series is arranged in rough chronological order.
  - Interior, passengers (2 photos + 1 email), 1983 December (Digital folder 20160714, Digital file 2_1-2, email)
  - Passengers, station (1 photo + 1 email), 1983 December (Digital folder 20170728, Digital file 8_1, email)
  - Interiors, stations, passengers (3 photos + 1 email), circa 1985 (Digital folder 20160329, Digital file 1_1-3, email)
  - No. 7 train heading into Manhattan from Queens (1 photo + 1 email), circa 1985 (Digital folder 20170713, Digital file 2_1, email)
    Lower Manhattan skyline in distance, including World Trade Center towers.
  - Interiors, passengers (2 photos + 1 email), 1980s (Digital folder 20170404, Digital file 2_1-2, email)
  - Interiors, stations, passengers, signage (15 photos + 1 email), 1980s, undated (Digital folder 20160330, Digital file 1_01-15, email)
    One photo, dating from the mid or early 1980s, was taken from the first car on a No. 7 line train coming from Queens into Manhattan and includes the Empire State Building in the background.
  - Brighton Beach subway entrance; Bleecker Street tiled signage (2 photos + 1 email), 1990s (Digital folder 20170621, Digital file 7_1-2, email)
  - Interiors, stations, passengers (9 photos + 1 email), circa 2000-2016 March (Digital folder 20160328, Digital file 1_1-9, email)
  - Interiors, stations, passengers, signage (18 photos + 1 email), undated (Digital folder 20160329, Digital file 2_01-18, email)
  - Interiors, passengers, concession stands, buskers, stations, signage (77 photos + 4 emails), 2000-2017 (Digital folder 20170617, Digital file 1_01-77, 4 emails)
  - Passengers, stations (4 photos + 1 email), 2000-2017 (Digital folder 20170619, Digital file 4_1-4, email)
  - Station concession stand (1 photo + 1 email), 2006 July (Digital folder 20170512, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - Vendor of winter garb in station (1 photo + 1 email), 2007 January (Digital folder 20170510, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - Buskers, passengers in station (3 photos + 2 emails), 2007, 2017 (Digital folder 20170518, Digital file 4_1-3, 2 emails)
  - Interior, passengers, 2014 August (Digital folder 20170703, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Interior, passengers (6 photos + 1 email), 2015 November 19 (Digital folder 20151126, Digital file 2_1-6, email)
  - Interior, passengers (2 photos + 1 email), 2016 March 25 (Digital folder 20160327, Digital file 2_1-2, email)
  - Interiors, stations, passengers, signage, street view of elevated tracks (15 photos + 1 email), 2016? (Digital folder 20160405, Digital file 1_01-15, email)
  - Interiors, stations, passengers, signage (16 photos + 1 email), 2016? (Digital folder 20160401, Digital file 2_01-16, email)
  - Station, passengers (1 photo + 1 email), 2016 April (Digital folder 20160426, Digital file 1_1, email)
    Platform for 1,2,3 line trains at 42nd Street
  - Interior, passengers (1 photo + 1 email), 2016 November? (Digital folder 20161103, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Couple kissing on 59th Street subway platform (2 photos + 1 email), 2017 January 14 (Digital folder 20170114, Digital file 1_1-2, email)
  - Interior, passengers (3 photos + 1 email), 2017 March 19 (Digital folder 20170324, Digital file 1_1-3, email)
  - Interiors, stations, passengers, tracks (3 photos + 1 email), 2017 March? (Digital folder 20170326, Digital file 1_1-3, email)
  - Interiors, stations, passengers (3 photos + 1 email), 2017 May 17 (Digital folder 20170518, Digital file 1_1-3, email)
  - Interior, passengers (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 June 14 (Digital folder 20170614, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Passengers, station, interiors (11 photos + 3 emails), 2017 June 21 (Digital folder 20170621, Digital file 6_01-11, 3 emails)
  - Interior, passengers (4 photos + 1 email), 2017 June (Digital folder 20170712, Digital file 1_1-4, email)
  - 50th Street station turnstiles (2 photos + 1 photo), 2017 July 17 (Digital folder 20170717, Digital file 2_1-2, email)
  - Subway coach advertisements (3 photos + 2 emails), 2017 July 26 (Digital folder 20170727, Digital file 1_1-3, 2 emails)
    Two images of "Subway Library" book downloads and one of "see something, say something" public safety ad.
  - Busker on keyboard in station (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 August 23 (Digital folder 20170823, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - Escalators at Lexington and 59th Street station (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 October 4 (Digital folder 20171005, Digital file 2_1, email)
- Series D.VII. Events, 1968-2017; 56.5 Megabytes (300 digital images in JPG format)
  The series includes photos that center on events and activities in the life of New Yorkers. These include a large set of photos taken at the 2015 Gay Pride Parade. The series also holds photos from the Macy's Thanksgiving Day Parade, images from Times Square where celebrants re-enacted the famous Eisenstadt 1945 photo of "The Kiss" in 2015, and other events. The series and the specific photos to place in it was established by the processing archivist.
  - Chief Judge Stanley Fuld swearing in Charles D. Brietel as a Judge of the New York Court of Appeals (1 photo + 1 email), 1968 January (Digital folder 20160718, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Thanksgiving Day Parade balloons (3 photos + 1 email), 1982 November (Digital folder 20160803, Digital file 4_1-3, email)
    Includes Olive Oyl, Kermit the Frog and Mickey Mouse.
  - Thanksgiving Day Parade balloons (5 photos + 1 email), 1980s (Digital folder 20151126, Digital file 1_1-5, email)
    Woody Woodpecker, Snoopy, Betty Boop, Donald Duck and Mickey Mouse.
  - Jimmy Connors playing in the US Open (8 photos + 1 email), 1983 September (Digital folder 20160714, Digital file 5_1-8, email)
  - Marchers in St. Patrick's Day Parade (1 photo + 1 email), 2003 March (Digital folder 20170612, Digital file 1_1, email)
    View from 3 or 4 floors above the marchers.
  - New York Marathon at Central Park (4 photos + 1 email), 2005 November (Digital folder 20170509, Digital file 2_1-4, email)
  - Last game at Yankee Stadium (2 photos + 1 email), 2008 September 21 (Digital folder 20170713, Digital file 1_1-2, email)
    View from seats above home plate, players on the field. Photographs by Harmon's son, Michael Harmon.
  - Gay Pride Parade (184 photos + 4 emails), 2015 June 28 (Digital folder 20150630, Digital file 1_001-184, 4 emails)
    Includes images of the parade participants, spectators, rainbow flags, street vendors, surroundings (e.g., as the parade passes the Stonewall and Duplex), New York City Mayor Bill de Blasio and his family who marched in the parade, and Grand Marshals Ian McKellan and Derek Jacobi.
  - 70th Anniversary of VJ Day & the end of WWII (30 photos + 1 email), 2015 August 14 (Digital folder 20150814, Digital file 1_01-30, email)
    Images from Times Square where celebrants re-enacted the famous Eisenstadt 1945 photo of "The Kiss."
  - Telecast of "Otello" in Times Square (24 photos + 1 email), 2015 September 21 (Digital folder 20150922, Digital file 1_01-24, email)
    Opening night performance of the opera at Lincoln Center, telecast to a large screen for public viewing in Times Square. Includes images of Times Square signage, spectators, and scenes from the telecast. The final photo in the set is of the photographer, Steve Harmon.
  - Security for President-elect Donald Trump (21 photos + 1 email), 2016 November 10 (Digital folder 20161110, Digital file 1_01-21, email)
    Security measures along 5th Avenue from the corner of 57th Street (at Tiffany's) to 53rd Street (at Trump Tower).
  - "Rei Kawakubo/Comme des Garcons Art of the In-Between" exhibition at the Metropolitan Museum of Art (17 photos + 1 email), 2017 July 22 (Digital folder 20170722, Digital file 1_01-17, email)
    Images of exhibited artworks.
- Series D.VIII. Various Other Subjects, 1970s-2017; 54.5 Megabytes (212 digital images in JPG format)
  The series includes digital photographs that do not necessarily fit neatly into the other series. These include photos from outside New York City; still lifes of objects; details of cars, carriages and other vehicles; food cart close-ups; miscellaneous signage; particular artworks in museums; images of buildings, people, and other scenes that tend more to the stylized rather than documentary, such as views taken through rain-drizzled windows; and other varied images. The series and the specific photos to place in it was established by the processing archivist.
  - Dan Miller's General Store and Pollock-Krasner House (11 photos + 2 emails), 1970s?, 1995 (Digital folder 20130127, Digital file 1_01-11, 2 emails)
    Includes seven photos of the general store in Springs, East Hampton, Long Island (1970s?); three of the studio floor with trace remainders of Jackson Pollock's work and one of the house kitchen.
  - Bungalow Bar ice cream truck (1 photo + 1 email), circa 1978 (Digital folder 20160716, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Gumball machines (1 photo + 1 email), circa 1978 (Digital folder 20170127, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - "Saturday Morning Astronauts" [women under hair dryers at beauty salon] (1 photo + 1 email), circa 1978 (Digital folder 20170524, Digital file 1_1, email)
    House of George salon, Upper West Side, West End Avenue and 72nd Street
  - Product advertisement signage (1 photo + 1 email), circa 1980 (Digital folder 20170718, Digital file 2_1, email)
    Signs in window for Dentyne gum, Coca-Cola and cigarettes.
  - Winter oil delivery on West End Avenue (1 photo + 1 email), 1980s (Digital folder 20160108, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Automat. Detail of control panel (1 photo + 1 email), 1980s (Digital folder 20170416, Digital file 1_1, 1 email)
  - Traffic and pedestrian signage. Columbus Avenue and West 77th Street (1 photo + 1 email), 1980s (Digital folder 20170420, Digital file 1_1, 1 email)
  - Seltzer truck (1 photos + 1 email), 1980s? (Digital folder 20170227, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - Checker Cab (1 photo + 1 email), 1982 August (Digital folder 20160715, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - Stacks of Sunday New York Times (1 photo + 1 email), circa 1982 (Digital folder 20170613, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Stadium cigarette advertisement (1 photo + 1 email), 1983 November (Digital folder 20160714, Digital file 4_1, email)
    "Jumbotron" screen over stadium bleachers, possibly at Shea Stadium, with advertising.
  - Cars in Shea Stadium parking lot (1 photo + 1 email), 1983 November (Digital folder 20160803, Digital file 5_1, email)
  - Napeague, Long Island. Lobster Roll Restaurant (1 photo + 1 email), circa 1990 (Digital folder 20170126, Digital file 3_1, email)
  - U.S. President Bill Clinton playing saxophone at the Inaugural Ball, Union Station, Washington, DC (1 photo + 1 email), 1993 January (Digital folder 20170126, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Newspaper vending machine (1 photo + 1 email), 1994 September (Digital folder 20170929, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Yellow taxi cab with signage of fares (1 photo + 1 email), 1996 November (Digital folder 20171020, Digital file 4_1, email)
  - Yellow taxi cab, through rain-drizzled glass (1 photo + 1 email), 1997 April (Digital folder 20171002, Digital file 3_1, email)
  - "Wanted Dead Not Alive: Bin Laden" flyer taped to car (1 photo + 1 email), 2001 November (Digital folder 20171002, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - Mounted policeman in SoHo on West Broadway (1 photo + 1 email), 2006 January (Digital folder 20170511, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - Morning traffic on the Long Island Expressway in Queens (2 photos + 1 email), 2006 September 20 (Digital folder 20170510, Digital file 1_1-2, email)
  - Horse-drawn carriages (2 photos + 1 email), October 2006 (Digital folder 20170514, Digital file 3_1-2, email)
  - Chrysler Building elevators (2 photos + 2 emails), 2006-2007 (Digital folder 20170515, Digital file 1_1-2, 2 emails)
    Includes: 1) detail of art deco design on elevator door (October 2006); 2) view of elevator bank with women janitorial workers (May 2007).
  - Upper West Side parking garage fee signage (1 photo + 1 email), 2007 April (Digital folder 20170521, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Food carts on Broadway near Wall Street (2 photos + 1 email), 2011 April (Digital folder 20170619, Digital file 3_1-2, email)
  - Cell phone street vendor cart (1 photo + 1 email), 2013 April (Digital folder 20170620, Digital file 5_1, email)
  - Food carts at Metropolitan Museum of Art (3 photos + 1 email), 2014 April (Digital folder 20170620, Digital file 6_1-3, email)
  - Flock of Canadian geese flying over Manhattan east side (5 photos + 1 email), 2014 August (Digital folder 20170703, Digital file 2_1-5, email)
  - Rain drizzled images (29 photos + 1 email), 2015 October (Digital folder 20151004, Digital file 1_01-29, email)
    Includes views through rain-drizzled glass of Flatiron Building, Washington Square Arch, Chinatown and Little Italy storefronts, building exteriors, street scenes.
  - Still lifes of seltzer bottles (4 photos + 1 email), 2015 (Digital folder 20151203, Digital file 1_1-4, email)
  - Guggenheim Museum, interior (14 photos + 1 email), 2016 March? (Digital folder 20160303, Digital file 2_01-14, email)
    The photos center primarily on views of patrons on the spiral ramp and gallery alcoves from across the atrium or from higher levels.
  - Berkshire Bank in Hudson, NY (1 photo + 1 email), 2016 July 22 (Digital folder 20160723, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Visitors at Stuart Davis works at Whitney Museum (2 photos + 1 email), 2016 August (Digital folder 20160826, Digital file 1_1-2, email)
    Play on viewers' clothing in relation to artworks.
  - New York State Court of Appeals, Albany (13 photos + 1 email), 2016 October 14 (Digital folder 20161019, Digital file 1_01-13, email)
    Mostly interiors, two exterior details.
  - Saratoga Springs & Racetrack (20 photos + 2 emails), 2016 October (Digital folder 20161020, Digital file 1_01-20, 2 emails)
    9 photos of racetrack taken off-season (no people) and 11 photos of mansions on North Broadway.
  - Horse-drawn carriages (7 photos + 2 emails), undated (Digital folder 20170114, Digital file 3_1-7, 2 emails)
    In and around Central Park, and in street traffic beyond the Park.
  - Docent using IPAD at Morgan Library Museum (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 March 19 (Digital folder 20170324, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - Rain drizzled images of Riverside Drive (39 photos + 1 email), 2017 April (Digital folder 20170404, Digital file 1_01-39, email)
  - Guggenheim Museum, interior (21 photos + 1 email), 2017 April (Digital folder 20170408, Digital file 1_01-21, email)
    Views of patrons and guards framed by the building's interior spiral architecture, artworks, self-portrait.
  - Bird roadkill on two-lane highway shoulder (1 photo +1 email), undated (Digital folder 20170605, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Child viewing art at the Cleveland Museum (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 June 25 (Digital folder 20170629, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Bus taking passengers on 5th Avenue at 53rd Street (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 July 7 (Digital folder 20170707, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Phone booths (1 photo + 1 email), undated (Digital folder 20170727, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Rain drizzled images of Upper West Side, 75th Street and Broadway (6 photos + 1 email), 2017 August 18 (Digital folder 20170818, Digital file 1_1-6, email)
  - Bethel, NY. Max Yasgur's barn (1 photo + 1 email), undated (Digital folder 20171024, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Fire engine (2 photos + 1 email), 2017 September (Digital folder 20171030, Digital file 1_1-2, email)
- Series P.I. Photographic Prints, 1942, 1970s-2011; 1.5 Linear feet in 1 flat box and 1 flat file folder
  The series includes photographic prints from the photographer. Notable in the series is a set of over 200 slides of Manhattan's Upper West Side from the 1980s and a set of photographs from the Times Square area of the late 1970s-1980s. The series also includes one 1942 wedding invitation.
  The series is arranged by size of the print and subject matter.
  - 19 color photographs, 8-1/2 x 11 in., Lower East Side, circa 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Includes 19 photographs taken by Stephen Harmon on the Lower East Side of Manhattan, New York City, in the mid-1980s. All the photographs are color, 8-1/2 x 11 inch prints. The photographs emphasize storefronts, signage of businesses, and building facades, with some wide angle views of rows of buildings. Pedestrians appear in several, most often in connection with street vendors.
    Identified streets represented in the photographs are Orchard (11), Essex (4), Grand (2), and Rivington (1). Storefronts and buildings that are the focus of photographs include Fine & Klein Handbags, Adler's Mens Wear (and nearby businesses and street vendors), Orchard Bootery, Beckenstein Home Fabrics, Inc., Ideal Hosiery, and Louis Stavsky Co. Hebrew religious supples & books. Photographs centered on signage include H. Eckstein & Sons, Leibel Bistritzky's kosher gourmet foods, a Judaica/Hebrew religious articles business at 45 Essex, and Blue Chip handkerchiefs & scarfs.
    Gift, April 2018.
  - 29 color photographs, 11 x 14 in. Times Square sex shops and movie theaters., 1980s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    All signed and numbered 3/40. Includes theater marquees, lobbies, storefronts, video stores, and Howard Johnson's neon sign. (See also Series D.I for digital versions of these and other related photographs.) Gift, October 2014.
  - 210 color slides, 2 x 2 in., Upper West Side, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Taken in the 1980s at the request of a civic organization, Landmark West, in connection with preservation efforts, the photographs include exteriors and details of notable buildings (Dakota, San Remo, Apthorp, Beresford, Belleclair, Pythian, Dorilton, Hotel Des Artistes, Portuguese Synagogue, Central Savings Bank, Ansonia, and others), views of brownstones, and various street views of Columbus, Amsterdam, and West End avenues, Broadway, and various streets ranging up to about 106th. Gift, 2014.
  - 11 color photographs, 8-1/2 x 11 in., Checker Cabs, circa 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photograph album, 6 x 4 in., Columbus Day Parade, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Includes various politicians marching in the parade, including Walter Mondale, Geraldine Ferraro, Mario Cuomo, Ed Koch, and Andrew Stein, and also Sophia Loren.
  - 14 color photographs, 6 x 4 in. Various subjects, 1970s-2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Beauty parlor customers, Bethesda Fountain in snow, subway car with graffiti and passengers, Chrysler Building gargoyle, fire escapes, storefronts on Broadway at West 164th Street, Brighton Beach subway station entrance, Gray's Papaya on Amsterdam at 72nd, rainy night scene on Broadway, and World Trade Center towers burning on 9/11. Also a Polaroid of Donald Trump, Sanford (Sandy) Weil, and Robert Savin at black tie dinner. Gift, December 2012.
  - 10 color photographs, 8-1/2 x 11 in., Various subjects, 1970-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)